Register of the Kurt Richard Grossmann Papers, 1913-1973
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, c.1933-1972 (Box 16-36)
  - "Report on my visit to Prof. William Haber on July 17, 1948, in Heidelberg," Mimeographed copy. (Folder 31: 56)
  - "Report on the violation of human rights through the building of the wall in Berlin on August 13, 1961," Mimeographed copy., n.d. (Folder 31: 57)
  - "Republikaner: Lindsay und Nixon haben ihre spezifischen Sorgen," (Republicans: L. and N. have their specific worries), Vorwaerts, (Printed copy)., March 27, 1969. (Folder 31: 58)
  - "Republikaner suchen einen Sieger," (Republicans are looking for a winner), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., October 26, 1967. (Folder 31: 59)
  - "Rescue is Still Possible," Bulletin, Czech. Jewish Representative Committee, Mimeographed copy., n.d. (Folder 31: 60)
  - "Restitution is Indivisible," Congress Weekly, Printed copy., January 3, 1955. (Folder 32: 1)
  - Restitution News, edited by and with contributions by Grossmann. Mimeographed and photographic copies.
    - 1967. (Folder 32: 2)
    - 1968. (Folder 32: 3)
    - 1969. (Folder 32: 4)
    - 1970. (Folder 32: 5)
  - "Retter und Gerettete," (Savior and saved), Typescript. (Folder 32: 6)
  - "Return to Basic Principles of Universal Declaration of Human Rights in Berlin Advocated," Typescript and mimeographed copy. (Folder 32: 7)
  - Review, The Assassin, by Uri Levi, Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 32: 8)
  - Review, Bericht, eines Beauftragten, by Felix E. Shinnar, Aufbau, Printed copy., November 10, 1967. (Folder 32: 9)
  - Review, Braunbuch: Kriegs- und Naziverbrecher in der BRD, by the German Democratic Republic, Aufbau, Printed copy., April 14, 1969. (Folder 32: 10)
  - Review, Child of the Holocaust, by Jack Kuper, Aufbau, Printed copy., January 3, 1969. (Folder 32: 11)
  - Review, Days of Fire, by Samuel Katz, Aufbau, Printed copy., December 20, 1968. (Folder 32: 12)
  - Review, The Death Factory, by Ota Kraus and Erich Kulka, Aufbau, Printed copy., July 15, 1966. (Folder 32: 13)
  - Review, Deutschlands Weg nach Israel, edited by Rolf Vogel, Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 32: 14)
  - Review, Diary of a Nightmare, by Ursula von Kardorff, Aufbau, Printed copy., April 29, 1966. (Folder 32: 15)
  - Review, Einladung nach Israel, by Dagmar Nick, Aufbau, Printed copy., August 23, 1968. (Folder 32: 16)
  - Review, Gerechtigkeit in Jerusalem, by Gideon Hausner, Rheinischer Merkur, Printed copies., March 15, 1968. (Folder 32: 17)
  - Review, German and Jew, by John K. Dickenson, Aufbau, Printed copy., September 20, 1968. (Folder 32: 18)
  - Review, Gestorben fuer Oesterreich, by Herbert Steiner, Aufbau, Printed copy., May 30, 1969. (Folder 32: 19)
  - Review, Ich werde die Wahrheit sagen, by Alfred Kantor, Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 32: 20)
  - Review, International Fascism, by Walter Laqueur, Aufbau, Printed copy., April 14, 1967. (Folder 32: 21)
  - Review, Die Juden in Hamburg, 1800-1850, by Helga Krohn, Aufbau, Printed copy., January 29, 1971. (Folder 32: 22)
  - Review, A Night of Watching, by Elliot Arnold, Aufbau, Typescript and printed copy., July 12, 1968. (Folder 32: 23)
  - Review, Die NPD, by Reinhard Kuehnl, Aufbau, Typescript and printed copy., April 26, 1968. (Folder 32: 24)
  - Review, Otto Bauer, Tragoedie oder Triumph, by Otto Leichter, Vorwaerts, Typescript (carbon copy), 1971. (Folder 32: 25)
  - Review, Politische Orientierung der Juden in Deutschland, by Jacob Toury, Aufbau, Printed copy., March 8, 1968. (Folder 32: 26)
  - Review, Russland im Krieg, by Alexander Werth, Aufbau, Printed copy., June 4, 1965. (Folder 32: 27)
  - Review, Die Sonnenblume, by Simon Wiesenthal, Aufbau, Printed copy., April 30, 1971. (Folder 32: 28)
  - Review, Staatsmann ohne Staat, by Nahum Goldmann, Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 32: 29)
  - Review, The Story of Hitler's SS, by Heinz Hoehne, Aufbau, Printed copy., May 29, 1970. (Folder 32: 30)
  - Review, They Fought Back, by Yuri Suhl, Aufbau, Printed copy., March 25, 1967. (Folder 32: 31)
  - Review, Two Germanies, Peter Lust, Aufbau, Printed copy., December 2, 1966. (Folder 32: 32)
  - Review, The Vanishing Swastika, by Christopher Emmet and Norbert Muhlen. Mimeographed copy. (Folder 32: 33)
  - Review, Die Wasser teilten sich nicht, by Arthur D. Morse, Aufbau, Printed copy., March 28, 1969. (Folder 32: 34)
  - Review, Wegweiser durch die juedische Geschichte, (Guide to Jewish history), by Jacob Robinson et al., Mimeographed copy., 1961. (Folder 32: 35)
  - Review, Weissbuch in Sachen Sinjawskij/Daniel, edited by Alexander Ginsburg, Aufbau, Printed copy., December 29, 1967. (Folder 32: 36)
  - Review, When Compassion was a Crime, by H. D. Leuner, Aufbau, Pricopy., March 3, 1967. (Folder 32: 37)
  - Review, Wohin treibt die Bundesrepublik? by Karl Jaspers, Aufbau, Printed copy., December 9, 1966. (Folder 32: 38)
  - "Die Revision der Entschaedigungs-Rententabellen," (The revision of the restitution pension tables), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and Printed copy., August 3, 1970. (Folder 33: 1)
  - "Rheinmetall und die Sklavenarbeiter," (Rheinmetall and slave workers), Aufbau, Printed copy., March 11, 1966. (Folder 33: 2)
  - "Richard Nixon und die Presse," Tagwacht, Printed copy., December 29, 1970. (Folder 33: 3)
  - "Richard Van Dyck," Aufbau, Printed copy., October 14, 1966. (Folder 33: 4)
  - "Das Riesenwerk der Wiedergutmachung," (The giant work of restitution), Sueddeutsche Zeitung, Printed copy., January 31, 1960. (Folder 33: 5)
  - "Righteous Gentiles in Germany: Unsung heroes," Encyclopedia Judaica, Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 33: 6)
  - "Robert Kennedy urges Federal Republic of Germany to Provide Fair and Just Indemnification," Mimeographed copy. (Folder 33: 7)
  - "Robert M.W. Kempner, der 70jaehrige Aktivist," Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., October 17, 1969. (Folder 33: 8)
  - "Romney, Nixon und andere, das Kandidatenrennen bei den USA Republikaner," (R., N, and others, the candidate race of the US Republicans), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., December 14, 1966. (Folder 33: 9)
  - "Die Rosenbergs," Typescript (carbon copy)., c.1952. (Folder 33: 10)
  - "Ruck nach Rechts, Amerika auf dem Wege zum Ordnungsstaat," (Shift to the right, America on the way to a regulated state), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy, October 21, 1970. (Folder 33: 11)
  - "Rueck- und Ausblick an der Jahreswende," (Looking forwards and backwards at New Years), Tagwacht, Printed copy., December 24, 1969. (Folder 33: 12)
  - "Rueckschlag fuer Gewerkschaften in den USA Wahlen," (Defeat for unions in the US elections), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., November 30, 1966. (Folder 33: 13)
  - "Rufmord an Martin Luther King," Tagwacht, Printed copy., August 24, 1970. (Folder 33: 14)
  - "Rusk gegen Gromyko," (R. vs. G.), Tagwacht, Printed copy., October 12, 1968. (Folder 33: 15)
  - "Schafft Nixon eine Koalition?" (Is N. creating a coalition?), Tagwacht, Printed copy., November 11, 1968. (Folder 33: 16)
  - "Schatten fallen auf das Wiedergutmachungswerk," (Shadows fall on restitution work), Mimeographed copy., December 14, 1964. (Folder 33: 17)
  - "Scherbenhaufen der Wiedergutmachung," (Shattered fragments of restitution), Aufbau, Printed copy., December 31, 1965. (Folder 33: 18)
  - "Schicksalsstunde fuer americanische Demokraten," (Fateful hour for American Democrats), Tagwacht, Printed copy., August 23, 1968. (Folder 33: 19)
  - "Schlappe Nixons in Angelhaken und daheim," (N.'s failure in 'the fishhook' and at home), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., July 9, 1970. (Folder 33: 20)
  - "Schleusen des Extremismus, der Kampf zwischen amerikanischen Juden und Negern," (Dammed up extremism, the struggle between American Jews and blacks), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., February 13, 1969. (Folder 33: 21)
  - "Schlussgesetz, Debatte im Bundestag," (Final law, debate in the German parliament), Aufbau, Printed copy., November 29, 1963. (Folder 33: 22)
  - "Schlussgesetz mit Mehrheit vom Bundesrat verabschiedet," (Final law recessed with majority of the upper house), Aufbau, Printed copy., July 16, 1965. (Folder 33: 23)
  - "Schlussgesetz vor der Verabschiedung-Einigung im Ausschuss," (Final law before the recess, agreement in committee), Aufbau, Printed copy., July 9, 1965. (Folder 33: 24)
  - "Schlussgesetze gehen zum Bundestag," (Final laws go to the Parliament), Aufbau, Printed copy., July 9 1965. (Folder 33: 25)
  - "Ein Schritt voran in Amerika, zwei Buergermeisterwahlen mit farbigen Ergebnis," (A step forward in America, blacks win two mayoral elections), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., November 23, 1967. (Folder 33: 26)
  - "Schuldilemma: Auch in America streikt man fuer Reformen," (School dilemma, even in America, people strike for reforms), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., January 23, 1969. (Folder 33: 27)
  - "Schuesse aus dem Dunkeln," (Shots in the dark), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy., June 2, 1971. (Folder 33: 28)
  - "Schweiz, Spanien, Afrika: die Hilfsaktionen gehen weiter," (Switzerland, Spain, Africa, aid committees continue work), Aufbau, Printed copy., November 27, 1942. (Folder 33: 29)
  - "648 zum Tode verurteilte warten," (648 people, sentenced to death, are waiting), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., July 3, 1971. (Folder 33: 30)
  - "Seltsame Entschaedigungsfaelle," (Strange restitution cases), Aufbau, Printed copy., February 16, 1962. (Folder 33: 31)
  - "Der Senator nahm auch Geschenke an," (The Senator accepted gifts), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., April 6, 1967. (Folder 33: 32)
  - "Sex und das ungeborene Kind," (Sex and the unborn child), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., November 21, 1969. (Folder 33: 33)
  - "Shielding Victims of War," Congress Weekly, Printed copy., May 9, 1949. (Folder 33: 34)
  - "Sidney Mendel," Aufbau, Typescript and printed copy., November 24, 1967. (Folder 33: 35)
  - "Die siebente Krise Richard Nixons," (R. N.'s seventh crisis), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 33: 36)
  - "Sieg der Elefanten?" (Victory for the elephants?), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., October 22, 1970. (Folder 33: 37)
  - "Siegmund Weltlinger, 80 Jahre," Aufbau, Printed copy., March 25, 1966. (Folder 33: 38)
  - "Sind die Schwarzen Panther eine Staatsgefahr?" (Are the Black Panthers a threat to the state?), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., February 5, 1970. (Folder 33: 39)
  - "The Situation of the Jews on the Eve of Germany's Defeat," Mimeographed copy., n.d. (Folder 33: 40)
  - "Sklaven ihrer Partei," (Slaves of their party), Aufbau, Printed copy., April 13, 1951. (Folder 33: 41)
  - "Sklavenarbeiter muessen entschaedigt werden," (Slave workers must receive restitution), Aufbau, Printed copy., June 2, 1967. (Folder 33: 42)
  - "So you,too, are a German baiter?" Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 33: 43)
  - "Spielt Nixon in Laos zu hoch?" (Is Nixon taking too big a chance in Laos?), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy., March 8, 1971. (Folder 33: 44)
  - "Spionage-Affaere Frenzel," (Spy incident Frenzel), Aufbau, Printed copy., November 18, 1960. (Folder 33: 45)
  - "Der Stand der Entschaedigungs in Zahlen," (The status of restitution in numbers), Aufbau, Printed copy., April 5, 1963. (Folder 33: 46)
  - "Starkes Echo in New York nach der Unterzeichnung der Luxemburger Abkommen," (Strong echo in N.Y. after the signing of the Luxemburg agreement), Allgemeine, Printed copy., n.d. (Folder 33: 47)
  - "Statistik ist interpretierbar. Was bedeutet positive Erledigung?" (Statistics can be interpreted. What is the meaning of a positive settlement?), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., October 1, 1961. (Folder 33: 48)
  - "Statt Auslandshilfe Solidaritaer?" (Instead of foreign aid, solidarity?), Tagwacht, Printed copies, November 12, 1971. (Folder 33: 49)
  - "Steht Deutschland an einem geistigen Kreuzweg?" (Is Germany at a spiritual cross road?), Holograph and typescript. (Folder 33: 50)
  - "Die Stiefkinder der Wiedergutmachung," (The stepchildren of restitution), Aufbau, Printed copy., July 29, 1966. (Folder 33: 51)
  - "Streifzuege durch Westdeutschland," (Wandering through West Germany), Sueddeutsche Zeitung, Printed copy., February 9, 1961. (Folder 33: 52)
  - "Streik gegen die USA Regierung," (Strike against the US government), Tagwacht, Printed copy., April 2, 1970. (Folder 33: 53)
  - "Streitbar auf amerikanisch," (Contentiousness American style), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., December 21, 1967. (Folder 33: 54)
  - "Die Studenten sind eine politische Belastung," (The students are a political liability), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy., August 29, 1970. (Folder 33: 55)
  - "Study on the Opinion of German Newspapers Concerning the Treatment of the Restitution Question," Mimeographed copy., June 9, 1958. (Folder 33: 56)
  - "Suehne oder Rache fuer den Mord an Robert F. Kennedy," (Retribution or revenge for the murder of R.F.K.), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., May 2, 1969. (Folder 33: 57)
  - "Synagoga in Recklinghausen," New Yorker Staats-Zeitung, Printed copies., December 10, 1960. (Folder 33: 58)
  - "Ein Tag in USA, was gibt's Neues?" (A day in the US, what's new?), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., April 24, 1970. (Folder 33: 59)
  - "Taten der Guete in dunklen Tagen," (Deeds of kindness in dark days), Aufbau, Printed copy., March 29, 1968. (Folder 33: 60)
  - "Die Tauben und das kleinere Uebel," (The doves and the lesser evil), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., October 24, 1968. (Folder 33: 61)
  - "Teds Leiden," (Ted's suffering), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., July 16, 1970. (Folder 33: 62)
  - "Teure Krankheit, der Gang zum Arzt ist in den USA 'eine Reise wert'" (Expensive illness, going to the doctor in the US is 'worth a trip'), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., July 17, 1969. (Folder 33: 63)
  - "Der tiefere Sinn des Bundesratsbeschlusses," (The deeper meaning of the decision of the upper house), Aufbau, Printed copy., June 25, 1965. (Folder 33: 64)
  - "Der Tod der Protestbewegung war mehr als uebertrieben," (The death of the protest movement was more than exaggerated), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 33: 65)
  - "Tom Mooney, ein Opfer Papens?" (T.M., a victim of Papens?), Die Zukunft, Printed copy., January 20, 1939. (Folder 33: 66)
  - "Der tote Tucholsky lebt," (The dead Tucholsky lives), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., October 23, 1970. (Folder 33: 67)
  - "Das tragische Drama des Chicagoer Aufruhrprozesses," (The tragic drama of the Chicago upheaval trial), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 33: 68)
  - "The Trial Against World Jewry that Never Took Place," National Jewish Monthly, Printed copy., November 1958. (Folder 33: 69)
  - "Tschechoslovakei nach dreissig Jahren wieder besucht," (Czechoslovakia visited again after 30 years), Typescript., c. 1968. (Folder 33: 70)
  - "Tutti fratelli--Wir sind alle Brueder" un souvenir de Solferino 100 Jahre alt," (We are all brothers, a souvenir of Solferino 100 years old), Mimeographed copy., March 4, 1962. (Folder 33: 71)
  - "Twenty-five Years Later: Illusions versus Reality," Typescript and carbon copy. (Folder 33: 72)
  - "Ueber den Vereinten Nationen kreist der Pleitegeier," (UN threatened by bankruptcy) Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., October 15, 1971. (Folder 34: 1)
  - "Die ueberholte Hallstein-Dokrin," (The out of date Hallstein doctrine), Aufbau, Printed copy., March 5, 1965. (Folder 34: 2)
  - "Die uebersehene Ursache: Verfaelschungen und Gehaessigkeit um die Wiedergutmachung," (The overlooked cause: falsifications and hostility concerning restitution), Aufbau, Printed copies., September 6, 1963. (Folder 34: 3)
  - "Um das Haushaltssicherungsgesetz," (About the law for economizing), Aufbau, Printed copy., January 14, 1966. (Folder 34: 4)
  - "Um den erblosen juedischen Besitz in Deutschland," (About heirless Jewish property in Germany), Mimeographed copies. (Folder 34: 5)
  - "Um die Doeblinger Rothschild Gaerten," (About the Rothschild gardens in Doebling), Aufbau, Printed copy., June 8, 1962. (Folder 34: 6)
  - "Um die Hinrichtung der Rosenbergs," (About the execution of the Rosenbergs), Frankfurter Rundschau, Typescript and printed copies., January 7, 1953. (Folder 34: 7)
  - "Der umstrittene Richter und Jude Abe Fortas," (The controversial judge and Jew A.F.), Aufbau, Printed copy., May 15, 1969. (Folder 34: 8)
  - "Der umstrittene Warren-Bericht," (The controversial Warren Report), Boletin informativo, November 1966. (Folder 34: 9)
  - Die unbesungenen Helden, (The unsung heroes), final form published in Berlin, Arani Verlag, 1957.
    - Fragment, Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 34: 10)
    - Research material, Typescripts., c. 1956. (Folder 34: 11)
    - Publicity, Typescript and printed copies., 1957-1962. (Folder 34: 12-14)
    - Reviews, Printed and typescript copies., 1957-1962. (Folder 34: 15-18)
    - References in the press, Typescript and printed copies., 1957-1962. (Folder 34: 19)
  - "Die unbesungenen Helden," Tribuene, Nr. 4, Photocopy., 1962. (Folder 34: 20)
  - "Die unbesungenen Helden," Page proofs., n.d. (Folder 34: 21)
  - "Die unbesungenen Helden," speech, Typescript (carbon copy)., November 22, 1964. (Folder 34: 22)
  - "Die unbesungenen Helden, Gedanken zur Bruederlichkeitswoche," (Thoughts on brotherhood week), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 34: 23)
  - "Die unbesungenen Helden und das Entschaedigungsrecht," (Unsung heroes and the right to restitution), Aufbau, Typescript and printed copies., July 26, 1968. (Folder 34: 24)
  - "Und es bewegt sich nichts," (And it does not move), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 35: 1)
  - "An unfulfilled Testament," Congress Weekly, Printed copy., November 12, 1943. (Folder 35: 2)
  - "Ungerechtigkeiten oder Unebenheiten?" (Injustices or inconsistencies?), Aufbau, Printed copy., October 21, 1966. (Folder 35: 3)
  - "Unmoralisch, bis das Gesetz siegt, Filmzensur in USA," (Immoral until the law wins, film censorship in the US), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., January 5, 1967. (Folder 35: 4)
  - "Die UNO in der Sackgasse," (The UN in a dead end street), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., September 25, 1969. (Folder 35: 5)
  - "Das Unrecht an Oesterreichs Juden," (The injustice to Austria's Jews), Aufbau, Printed copy., November 26. (Folder 35: 6)
  - "Unrecognized Allies," The Nation, Printed copy., 1943. (Folder 35: 7)
  - "Unsere Refugees in den alliierten Laendern waehrend des Krieges," (Our refugees in the allied countries during the war), Aufbau, Printed copy. (Folder 35: 8)
  - "Unterdrueckungen und Menschenrechte," (Oppression and human rights), Typescript. (Folder 35: 9)
  - "Unverwirklichte Menschenrechte," (Unrealized human rights), Geist und Tat, Printed copy., August 1958. (Folder 35: 10)
  - "Unwiderstehlicher Zwang?" (Irresistible force?) Tagwacht, Printed copy., January 8, 1969. (Folder 35: 11)
  - "USA, das Land der unloesbarer Widersprueche," (US, the country of unsolvable contradictions), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., June 6, 1969. (Folder 35: 12)
  - "USA, die Armen warten," (US, the poor are waiting), Tagwacht, Printed copy., July 28, 1969. (Folder 35: 13)
  - "Die USA im Zeichen der dirigierten Wirtschaft," (US under an engineered economy), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., October 29, 1971. (Folder 35: 14)
  - "USA, Innenpolitik schwaecht aussenpolitische Potenz," (US, domestic policy weakens foreign policy strength), Tagwacht, Printed copy., September 28, 1968. (Folder 35: 15)
  - "USA, Krisen-Tagebuch," (US, crisis diary), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 35: 16)
  - "USA, Meinung ueber Reparationsverhandlungen," (US, opinion on reparation negotiations), Allgemeine, Duesseldorf, Printed copy., March 28, 1952. (Folder 35: 17)
  - "USA, sogar Gott muss bezahlen, was denkt das Ausland von der Schweiz?" (US, even God must pay, what does the rest of the world think of Switzerland?), Tagwacht, Printed copy., April 16, 1969. (Folder 35: 18)
  - "USA und CSSR," (US and Czechoslovakia), Tagwacht, Printed copy., August 31, 1968. (Folder 35: 19)
  - "Die USA und der Bonner Regierungswechsel," (US and the change of government in Bonn), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 35: 20)
  - "Die USA und Weimar, eine missglueckte Professoren-Konferenz," (US and Weimar, an unsuccessful professors conference), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., December 18, 1971. (Folder 35: 21)
  - "Veit Valentin und die Deutschen," (V.V. and the Germans), Typescript (carbon copy)., c. 1966. (Folder 35: 22)
  - "Die Vereinigten Staaten auf dem Wege zum Sozialstaat," (The US on the road to a socialist state), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 35: 23)
  - "Die Verfassungskrise," (Constitutional crisis), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., June 15, 1970. (Folder 35: 24)
  - "Verfolgte und Verjaehrungskompromiss," (The persecuted and the compromise on the statute of limitations), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 35: 25)
  - "Die Verfolgung der Juden hinter dem Eisernen Vorhang," (The persecution of the Jews behind the Iron Curtain), Die neue Zeitung, Printed copy., February 14, 1953. (Folder 35: 26)
  - "Vergebene Suenden," (Forgiven sins), Aufbau, Printed copy., December 22, 1967. (Folder 35: 27)
  - "Das vergessene deutsche Wunder," (The forgotten German miracle), Die Mahnung, Typescript and printed copies., July 1, 1966. (Folder 35: 28)
  - "Die vergessene Ehrenschuld," (The forgotten debt of honor), La Semana israelita, Printed copies., December 24, 1965. (Folder 35: 29)
  - "Die vergessenen Helden," Die Zeit, Printed copy., September 11, 1964. (Folder 35: 30)
  - "Verjaehrungsfrist, die Bundesrepublik an einem moralischen Kreuzweg," (Statute of limitations, West Germany at a moral cross road), Aufbau, Printed copy., January 8, 1965. (Folder 35: 31)
  - "Die Verjaehrungsfrist muss fallen," (The statue of limitations must be eliminated), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., January 2, 1961. (Folder 35: 32)
  - "Verletztes Voelkerrecht," (Violated international law), Aufbau, Printed copy., Augsut 15, 1969. (Folder 35: 33)
  - "Vertagung der Integration," (Postponing integration), Tagwacht, Printed copy., March 5, 1970. (Folder 35: 34)
  - "Der Vertrag mit dem Augenzwinkern," (The contract that winks), Berner Tagwacht, Printed copy., May 23, 1939. (Folder 35: 35)
  - "Verzweiflung statt Hoffnung," (Dispair instead of hope), Tagwacht, Printed copy., June 17, 1960. (Folder 35: 36)
  - "Viele sind inzwischen gestorben...Die Wiedergutmachung in Duetschland, Wunsch und Wirklichkeit," (Many have died in the meantime, restitution in Germany, wish and reality), Frankfurter Rundschau, Reprint., July 21, 1956. (Folder 35: 37)
  - "Vier Fragen an die Entschaedigungsbehoerden, um die Endphase der Wiedergutmachung," (Four questions for the indemnification officials, about the final phase of restitution), Aufbau, Printed copies., April 25, 1969. (Folder 35: 38)
  - "Viermillionenmal Tucholsky. Das Tucholskyarchiv, Spiegel einer phaenomenalen Renaissance," (T. four million times. The T. archive, mirror of a phenomenal Renaissance), Aufbau, Printed copy., October 30, 1970. (Folder 35: 39)
  - "Die 24. UN-Vollversammlung und der Kongress," (The 24th full session of the UN and Congress), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., January 8, 1970. (Folder 35: 40)
  - "Vietnam laehmt Amerika," (Viet Nam paralyzes America), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., August 1, 1968. (Folder 35: 41)
  - "Vietnam-Nixons Pferdefuss," (Viet Nam, N.'s flaw), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy, April 23, 1971. (Folder 35: 42)
  - "Vietnam und kein Ende, 45 000 Tote und 30 Milliarden Dollar sind den Amerikanern zuviel," (V. with no end, 45,000 dead and 30 billion dollars are too much for the Americans), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., October 9, 1969. (Folder 35: 43)
  - "Vietnam Veteranen schlagen Alarm, Nixon bleibt harthoerig," (V. veterans sound the alarm, N. remains hard of hearing), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., May 7, 1971. (Folder 35: 44)